# **Richard Hendriks**

richard.hendriks@piedpiper.com (912) 555-4321 Palo Alto, US piedpiper.com

## **Summary**

Richard hails from **Tulsa**. He has earned degrees from the University of Oklahoma and Stanford. (Go Sooners and Cardinals!) Before starting Pied Piper, he worked for Hooli as a part time software developer. While his work focuses on applied information theory, mostly optimizing lossless compression schema of both the length-limited and adaptive variants, his non-work interests range widely, everything from quantum computing to chaos theory. He could tell you about it, but THAT would NOT be a "length-limited" conversation!

#### **Skills**

• Web Development: HTML, CSS, Javascript

• Compression: Mpeg, MP4, GIF

# **Work Experience**

Pied Piper Apr 2014 — Present

CEO/President

- Build an algorithm for artist to detect if their music was violating copy right infringement laws
- · Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt
- Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores

**Hooli** Jan 2014 — Apr 2014

Senior Software Engineer

· Worked on optimizing the backend algorithms for Hooli

Software Engineer Jan 2013 — Jan 2014

• Contributed bugfixes and smaller features for Hooli

### Volunteering

CoderDojo Jan 2012 — Jan 2013

Global movement of free coding clubs for young people.

Awarded 'Teacher of the Month'

# **Education**

Teacher

Stanford Jun 2011 — Jan 2014

B.S

- **DB1101** Basic SQL
- CS2011 Java Introduction

# **Awards & Recognitions**

• **Digital Compression Pioneer Award**: There is no spoon.